# Todd A. Murphy

I am currently an Information Technology major with a Specialization in Network and Information Security. I am very experienced with electronics, computers and especially networking. In my free time, I enjoy designing circuits, printing them onto circuits boards and soldering components just so I can have another smart device controlled by Siri. As I continue my studies at NJIT, I plan on acquiring a minor in Mobile and Web Development.











## EDUCATION

# **Bachelor of Science in Information Technology**

**New Jersey Institute of Technology**Newark, NJ

GPA 3.81

Expected Graduation: May 2020

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE =

# Teacher's Assistant

New Jersey Institute of Technology

January 2018 – Present

Newark, NJ

- Class: IT114 Advanced Programming for Information Technology (JAVA)
- Assistant to the Teacher in all aspects such as: student help, grading and teaching
- Held office hours for 10 hours a week, outside of class, for extra help

# Technician

#### **NJIT Media Services**

Fall 2016 – Present

Newark, NJ

- Experienced in troubleshooting technical problems, especially under pressure

# Stagehand

I.A.T.S.E. Local 8

September 2014 – Present

Philadelphia, PA

- Responsible for all behind-the-scenes tech during live shows
- Operated many sound consoles, lighting consoles, and spotlights
- Experienced in being a backstage coordinator

#### Sound Engineer

**Investors Bank Performing Arts Center** September 2012 – June 2016 Washington Township, NJ

- Leader of the Technical Crew
- Responsible for the operation of multiple Allen & Heath Sound Consoles
- Successfully put on many shows involving many different sound arrays

#### Manager/Ice Maker

Rita's Water Ice

September 2005 – Present

Northfield, NJ

- Responsible for running the family business as lead manager
- Experienced in making water ice, waiting on customers and counting registers :

## LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE -



## John O. Mosely Leadership School

# Sigma Alpha Epsilon

July 2017

Phoenix, Arizona

 Explored leadership abilities, learned new skills and interacted with interesting undergraduates and alumni from around the Realm of Sigma Alpha Epsilon.

## AFFILIATIONS =

Treasurer & Webmaster

Sigma Alpha Epsilon Fraternity

Spring 2017 - Present

#### SOFTWARE -

- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- Fusion 360
- Word, Excel, PowerPoint
- Unity
- Android Studio
- Xcode
- Wireshark
- Experienced in macOS, Linux & Windows

# **COMPUTER LANGUAGES** •

- Python
- C++
- JAVA
- HTML & CSS
- C#: Unity
- JavaScript
- Swift
- PHP
- Arduino
- SQL

## PERSONAL PROJECTS =

#### **DIY HomeKit Enabled LED's**

• Siri-enabled lights from scratch.

Sigma Alpha Epsilon - NJIT Website

• Designed saenjit.com

#### WEBSITES



/tmurphy605



HTTP://TODDAMURPHY.ME